

oliverjjones1994@gmail.com (+44) 7983622465 oliverj.dev (wip - not yet hosted) aithub.com/ojones44

HARD SKILLS

Core Knowledge

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, NodeJS, Python

Libraries/Frameworks

React, Tailwind (limited), Bootstrap

Tools

GitHub, MongoDB, Postman, Netlify

SOFT SKILLS

Good Communicator Time Management Hands on Attitude Openess to Criticism Problem Solving

EDUCATION

Ipeco Apprenticeship

City & Guilds Mechanical Engineering Qualifications

Sep 2012 - Sep 2016

SEEVIC College

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in Engineering

Sep 2010 - Sep 2012

INTERESTS

Walking, reading, comedy, concerts, basketball, music, language, tech

PERSONAL INFO

DoB: 21/04/1994 Homeowner Full, clean UK driving license Single Essex, England

OLIVER JONES

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proactive, ambitious Junior Web Developer with 11 years of experience as an aerospace engineer. A team player with a strong foundation in time management and problem-solving. Driven by my newfound passion for web development, I'm looking to combine it with the critical skills I've learned as an engineer to build digital products that live on the web. I am confident in my ability to apply my skills and expertise to the software engineering field and excited to see where this journey takes me.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Self Learning
Web Development

Mar 2022 - present

As a self-taught developer, I have enjoyed dedicating my free time to honing new skills in front and back-end web development. Through a combination of courses, books, personal projects, and collaborative projects, I have started to gain a good understanding of what software engineering is all about.

My journey started with Python and the aid of a book, where I got to grips with how programming languages work. This helped me to understand some fundamentals of programming languages.

Moving onto web development, and following the completion of a Udemy course, I started to build some small projects using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Understanding how these work is a crucial step, so after the course I spent considerable time researching and practicing them.

Currently, I'm learning React where I have a couple of projects on the go. One is an ambitious project with one other collaborator, where we are attempting to build an app that can be used in the aerospace industry to aid all aspects of a manufacturing machine shop.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ipeco Holdings Ltd.

Apprentice Engineer / CNC Setter

Sep 2012 - Nov 2019

Completing City & Guilds Engineering Qualifications.
Gained experience through placements within the company.
Setting/Operating various machine tools across two machining disciplines.

Adhering to production orders, technical drawings and documentation.

Ipeco Holdings Ltd.

CNC Programming Engineer

Nov 2019 - present

Offline programming using CAD/CAM software (Edgecam & Hypermill) to design fixturing and produce components for 3 and 5 axis machining centres

ACHIEVEMENTS

2020 - 2021 Increased manufacturing output whilst decreasing business costs, saving ~£125,000/year.

2022 – 2023 Headed up a project for the purchase, preparation, programming and setup of two Matsuura MAM72-35V

machines. Machines running 24/7 within 3 months of

delivery.